lancaster.ac.uk 2017-11-19

# Privacy and Cookies Notice | Lancaster University

This privacy notice sets out how Lancaster University uses and protects any information that you give when you use our website.

Lancaster University is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy notice.

Lancaster University may change this notice from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page occasionally to ensure that you are happy with any changes. This notice is effective from 26th May 2012.

## 1\. How we use cookies

A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer's hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.

The University webservers collect anonymous information, like the IP address of your computer, the browser software used, the operating system, access times and pages visited. This information is used to monitor usage and to assess the effectiveness of the University website.

In some sections of the University website anonymous data such as browser type or IP address may be used to customise web page content. This information is used in an anonymous form to ensure appropriate and effective delivery of content.

Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.

You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. You should be aware that this may prevent you from taking full advantage of Lancaster University's website. If you are unsure how to do this, use your favourite search engine to look this up using the term 'declining cookies' with your browser name, or contact your local IT support for advice.

The tables below further explain which cookies Lancaster University uses and why:

#### Internal Cookies

Cookies|  | Name|  | Purpose  
---|---|---|---|---  
User Preferences Cookie | .ASPXANONYMOUS | Used to identify users' choices in form fields and show them as options the next time the user logs in.  
Web Room Booking | .ASPXAUTH | Authentication for online Room Bookings.  
Library patron type cookie | AlephPatType | Stores patron (user) type entered at login to avoid repeated prompting.  
CoSign | Cosign, cosign-lusionline, cosign-weblogin1, cosign-weblogin2, cosign-www | Used to identify and verify that the user has logged in via CoSign (single sign-in for password-protected content) across compliant University services.  
ASP Forms Authentication Cookie | DLHE Authentication | Used to identify and verify that the user has logged in via ASP.NET Forms Authentication.  
CoSign login cookie | exposedFactors | Used to identify which factors the user should authenticate with when signing into CoSign.  
Ezproxy session cookie | ezproxy | Stores session identifier for Ezproxy session. EZproxy is a Library online resource proxy server for off-campus users.  
Stats cookie | is_unique | Used by statcounter.com to count the number of unique visitors to the page.  
ASP Forms Authentication Cookie | LUSI_Student | Used to identify and verify that the user has logged in via ASP.NET Forms Authentication.  
Web Room Booking | MixedSecurity.ReturnUrl, wrb, WRBStyle | Used to enable Web Room Bookings.  
Single-sign-on for  
Ex Libris products | PDS_HANDLE | Supports single-sign-on across Ex Libris products.  
Style | style | Enables correct page display.  
Text size | textsize | Enables correct text size display.  
PASS | _nac_session_id | Used for user identification and tracking of authorisation attributes for user sessions.  
WebGuardian | _WebGuardian_session | User for user identification and tracking of authorisation attributes for user sessions.  
ResNet | resnet_session, toolbag | Used to identify users of the student residences network, provide interface customisation and track the progress of user sessions through the validation process.  
  
#### External Cookies

Cookies|  | Name|  | Purpose|  | More information  
---|---|---|---|---|---|---  
Survey Gizmo | SLU6E6O4KD82A4S985NYYRPD85FP8C, JX14XUNLRMZ6ZD1D0S7XLQP3PZ2TMH | Enables conference delegates to submit abstracts online. | [Survey Gizmo Privacy and Security Policies](http://www.surveygizmo.com/privacy/ "Link: Survey Gizmo Privacy and Security Policies")  
Athens | ath_da, ath_ltoken, ath_username, PHPSESSID | A 3rd party single-sign-on for Library online resources which enables single-sign-on across many online resources. | [ATHENS (Eduserv) Privacy policy](http://www.eduserv.org.uk/Help/Privacy-Policy "Link: ATHENS \(Eduserv\) Privacy policy")  
Disqus | disqus_unique, testcookie | Used to enable commenting by users, with integration to Facebook and other social networks. Disqus themselves use Google Analytics and Quantcast to track users of their commenting system. | [Disqus privacy policy](http://docs.disqus.com/help/30/ "Link: Disqus privacy policy")  
Facebook | Act, c_user, datr, lu, p, presence, s, xs | Facebook widget incorporating a 'like' button, enabling users to 'like' specific pages. | [Data Use policy](http://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/ "Link: Data Use policy")  
Flickr | BX, current_identity, fitoto, fldetectedlang, localization | Enables a Flickr slideshow widget to display photos as slideshows. | [Flickr Privacy Policy](http://www.flickr.com/help/privacy-policy/ "Link: Flickr Privacy Policy")  
Google Analytics | _utma, _utmb, _utmc, _utmz, PREF, NID, Rememberme, UA-1580171-1, UA-34489726-1 | These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited. | [Overview of privacy at Google](http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html "Link: Overview of privacy at Google")  
Mouseflow | mf_[session], mf_user | **mf_[session]**  identifies the browser session while it happens. The cookie is deleted as soon as the session ends, meaning when the user leaves the website. **mf_user**  establishes whether the user is a returning or first time visitor. | [Mouseflow cookie policy](https://mouseflow.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/206504175-What-is-your-cookie-policy- "Link: Mouseflow cookie policy")  
Quantcast | __QCA | These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited. | [Quantcast privacy policy](http://www.quantcast.com/how-we-do-it/consumer-choice/privacy-policy/ "Link: Quantcast privacy policy")  
Twitter | guest_id, pid | A Twitter widget in the footer of some pages enables visitors to tweet about the page. | [Twitter Privacy Policy](http://twitter.com/privacy "Link: Twitter Privacy Policy")  
Yahoo | BA, YLS, PH, CH, Yahoo_uk_hp, B, F, T, SSL | These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited. | [Yahoo Privacy Policy](http://info.yahoo.com/privacy/uk/yahoo/ "Link: Yahoo Privacy Policy")  
Youtube | Enablesapps.uploader, HSID, login_info, sid VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE, PREF, use_hitbox, demographics, watched_video_id_list_nLYix, itsessionid1000571795845, itvisitorid1000571795845 | Enables users to view embedded YouTube video. | [Information on Privacy at YouTube](http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en-GB/policies/privacy/ "Link: Information on Privacy at YouTube")  
Wordpress | wp-settings-time-1, wp-settings-1, wordpress_test_cookie, wordpress_logged_in_da97b4397da3d182f30465df2848f668, wordpress_da97b4397da3d182f30465df2848f668 | Used to authenticate logged-in users for Wordpress blogs, and store various settings. | [Information about Wordpress cookies](http://codex.wordpress.org/WordPress_Cookies "Link: Information about Wordpress cookies")  
AddThis | Loc, ssc, uit, bt, dt, di, uid, uvc, psc | AddThis is a social media/bookmarking widget. | [AddThis Privacy Policy](http://www.addthis.com/privacy/privacy-policy "Link: AddThis Privacy Policy")  
  
## 2\. Google Analytics

Google Analytics use traffic log cookies to gain information about the use that is made of pages on our website. We use the information from cookies to generate reports on the usage of our website which are used for evaluation and analysis. The purpose is to improve our website by tailoring it to the needs of users.

In addition to standard analytics parameters, we receive data via two Google Analytics Advertising Features:

  * 'Demographics and Interest Reporting' gives us greater insight into the _types_ of visitors we receive.
  * 'Remarketing with Google Analytics' allows Lancaster University's Google advertising campaigns to focus on _web browsers_ which have previously been used to visit directly-related pages of our website.

In all cases, no data specific to any identifiable user is retained.

As a user you can opt out of this process of collecting traffic log data. To do so please visit the following site which provides a browser add-on that enables a user to opt out - <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

## 3\. Links to other websites

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, [*.lancs.ac.uk](http://www.lancs.ac.uk/ "Link: Lancaster University home page") or *.lancaster.ac.uk, you should note that we do not have any control over other websites. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

## 4\. What we collect

In addition to using cookies on our website, we may collect the following information from you when you fill in a form on our website or have contact with us by letter, email, telephone or other means. We will always ask before we collect such information:

  * Name and job title
  * Contact information including email address
  * Demographic information such as postcode, preferences and interests
  * Information relevant to services offered by Lancaster University
  * Information relevant to surveys

## 5\. What we do with the information we gather

This information helps us to understand your needs and provide you with a better service, and in particular for the following reasons:

  * Internal record keeping
  * We may use the information to improve our products and services
  * We may periodically send promotional emails about new products, special offers or other information which we think you may find interesting using the email address which you have provided
  * From time to time, we may also use your information to contact you for market research purposes. We may contact you by email, phone, fax or mail. We may use the information to customise the website according to your interests
  * Other purposes which are advised at the point of collection, and in compliance with our Data Controller registration with the Information Commissioner's Office

## 6\. Security

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. Appropriate security measures are in place to protect against loss, misuse or alteration of information collected from you, including measures to prevent, as far as possible, access to University databases by parties other than Lancaster University.

## 7\. Controlling your personal information

You may choose to restrict the collection or use of your personal information in the following ways:

  * Whenever you are asked to fill in a form on the website, look for the box that you can click to indicate that you do not want the information to be used by anybody for direct marketing purposes
  * If you have previously agreed to us using your personal information for direct marketing purposes, you may change your mind at any time by writing to or emailing us at the address below.
  * We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required to do so by law.

You may request details of personal information which we hold about you under the Data Protection Act 1998. A fee of £10 will be payable to contribute to the associated administrative costs. If you would like a copy of the information held on you please visit <https://gap.lancs.ac.uk/dataprotection/subjectaccess/> or write to:

The Compliance Team  
Secretariat  
University House  
Lancaster University  
Lancaster LA1 4YW

If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please write to or email us at [compliance@lancs.ac.uk](mailto:compliance@lancs.ac.uk "Email: Compliance Team") as soon as possible, at the above address. We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.
